Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "W"
  - WILLARD, EMMA, 1787-1870 (Box 31, Folder 1200)
    - Autograph inscription, signed with initials, to Mrs. Sigourney
      Gift of Gordon S. Haight, August 1941
  - WILLIAMS, FRANCIS HOWARD, 1844-1922 (Box 31, Folder 1201)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Germantown, Pa., 1891 October 28
      Removed from: His Atman, [c1891]
  - WILLIS, CORNELIA (GRINNELL) (Box 31, Folder 1202)
    - ALS to George Pope Morris, Campton Village, N. H., 1862 June 10
      (Removed from: Morris's Poems... New York, 1854.
      Za.M8322.853pd)
  - WILLIS, NATHANIEL PARKER, 1806-1867 (Box 31, Folder 1203)
    - ALS to C. Butler, Idlewild, 1859 July 18
      Removed from: extra-illustrated
      Pierre Irving's Life and Letters of Washington Irving (New York, 1862-64)
  - WILSON, AUGUSTA JANE (EVANS), 1835-1909
    See: EVANS, AUGUSTA J. (AUGUSTA JANE), 1835-1909
  - WILSON, JAMES GRANT, 1832-1914 (Box 31, Folder 1204)
    - Photostat of ALS to Prof. [John] Fiske, Chicago, 1897 March 27
      Including ANS from John Fiske to
      [Justin] Winsor, Chicago, March 31 [1897], and Winsor's ANS in reply, together with AN in an unidentified hand, 2 leaves
      From original in possession of W. L. Pforzheimer
  - WISE, H. A. (HENRY AUGUSTUS). 1819-1869 (Box 31, Folder 1205)
    - List of his 4 works, arranged in order of merit, in his autograph and signed
      Aldis autograph collection
    - ALS to "Ma Lynche," Elizabeth City, 1849 December 2
      8 pages (2 leaves)
      Signed: H. A. Sabio
      Removed from: His Tales...1855
    - 3 ALS to Edward Everett, Bureau of Ordnance [Washington, D. C.], 1862 August, October
    - ALS [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: His Captain Brand... London, 1860
  - WISTER, OWEN, 1860-1938, 3 (Box 31, Folder 1206-1208)
    - ALS to Richard Watson Gilder, Philadelphia, Pa., 1900 December 13
    - ALS to Noble, Philadelphia, Thursday, February 8
      Removed from: copy of his Members of the family...New York, 1911
    - ANS to Miss Norton, [n. p.], 1915 March 12
  - WOOD, CLEMENT, 1888-1950 (Box 31, Folder 1209)
    - 13 TLS and 1 TPCS to Cyril Clemens, New York and Delanson, 1939-1948
      Purchased from Mr. Clemens, November. 1966, on D. Barney and W. L. Phelps funds
  - WOOD, RAY (Box 31, Folder 1210)
    - TLS to Carl Van Vechten, Raywood, Texas, 1939 February 18
      [Removed from: his Mother Goose in the Ozarks, [Raywood, Texas, c1938]]
      Gift of Carl Van Vechten, November 1946
  - WOODBERRY, GEORGE EDWARD, 1855-1930, 2 (Box 31, Folder 1211-1212)
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Tunis, Tunisia, 1908 April 10
    - ALS to Mr. Didier, Boston, Mass., 1890 May 1
    - ALS to Mr. K [name indecipherable], [n. p.], undated
    - ALS to Charles W(arren) Stoddard, New York, 1894 October 28
    - ALS to Mrs. Snow, Capri, 1910 September 21
      Gift of Harold Brody, 1954
    - ALS to E. C. Stedman, [New York], 1896 December 15
      Removed from: Tennyson. The princess ...New York, 1896
    - ALS to James Russell Lowell, Beverly, 1891 July 14
      Purchased with the Alvord fund, 1952
  - WOODBURY, JOSEPHINE CURTIS (Box 31, Folder 1213)
    - Presentation inscription to the library of Yale University, [n. p.], 1906 August 22
  - WOODWORTH, SAMUEL, 1784-1842 (Box 31, Folder 1214)
    - ANS to Joseph B. Boyd, New York, 1838 July 31
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Melodies, Duets,, 1831] Gift of Owen F. Aldis, 1911
    - ANS to [Peter] Force, New York, November 20
      [Enclosing printed prospectus for publishing "an original work, entitled New York: A Poem"]
  - WOOLF, BENJAMIN E. (Box 31, Folder 1215)
    - ALS to [E. C.] Stedman, Boston, 1889 March 20
      [Removed from: his Pounce and co., Boston [c1882]
      Za.W883.882p]
    - ALS to Arthur Stedman, Boston, 1889 May 8
  - WOOLLCOTT, ALEXANDER, 1887-1943 (Box 31, Folder 1216)
    - Legerdemain. Typescript (carbon)
      86 leaves
      "Sacha Guitry's "L'illusioniste" transposed to an English setting" Gift of the New York Public Library
  - WOOLSEY, SARAH CHAUNCEY, 1835-1905, 3 (Box 31, Folder 1217-1219)
    - ALS to "My dear child," Newport, R. I., February 6
      Signed with her pen-name: Susan Coolidge
    - ALS to Mr. Adams, Florence, Italy, 1873 March 25
    - ALS to Mrs. (Anne Charlotte (Lynch)) Botta, Princeton, N. J., 1879 August 17
    - ALS to Mr. Hardy, Newport, R. I., November 25
    - ALS to Mrs. Rogers, Newport, R. I., 1881 January 10
    - 4 ALS to Mr. Niles, Newport, R. I. and New Haven, Conn., [1892-1893]
      19 pages
    - "Every day is a fresh beginning": ms copy of verse commencing with this line. Signed with her pseudonym, "Susan Coolidge," and dated Newport, 1886 December 27
    - ALS to Miss Booth, Newport, R. I., 1879 January 21
      Bequest of Katherine Dreier
    - AL signed with her pseudonym, Susan Coolidge, to Mr. Reynolds, Newport, R. I., [1900] October 28
  - WOOLSON, CONSTANCE FENIMORE, 1840-1894 (Box 31, Folder 1220)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, St. Augustine, Fla., 1874 April 13
      (Removed from: her Castle nowhere: lake-country sketches. Boston, 1875.
      Za.W888.875)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Cooperstown, October 10
  - WORTMAN, DENIS, 1835-1922 (Box 31, Folder 1221)
    - America for the World: Facsimile of ms of poem, with ms note: "not yet published, May, 1898," signed D. W.
    - TLS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Saugerties, 1895 December 13
      With autographed postscript
  - WRIGHT, ALICE MORGAN (Box 31, Folder 1222)
    - Such Stuff as Dreams are Made On: typewritten copy
      116 pages
      From the estate of Miss Jordan, June 1941
  - WRIGHT, MABEL OSGOOD, 1859-1934 (Box 31, Folder 1223)
    - ALS to E. C. Stedman, [New York, ], 1894 April 6
      Removed from: Her Friendship of nature., 1894
  - WRIGHT, WILLARD HUNTINGTON, 1888-1939 (Box 31, Folder 1224)
    - McCormick, Julia Wright. [Sonnet]. Ms: 1 page First line, "O Dreamer, pray do not enthrone me so," signed and dated, 1906 August 8
      Purchased with Library Associates Fund
    - McGoarty, John S. Telegram to Willard Huntington Wright, Los Angeles, Cal., 1913 April 17
- "Y"
  - YOUNG, ART, 1866-1943 (Box 31, Folder 1225)
    - 2 ALS to Bolton Hall, Bethel, Conn., undated
  - YOUNG, LIVIA IONE (Box 31, Folder 1226)
    - TL to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Norwich, Conn., 1907 December 26
      [Removed from: her At evening time. New York, [c1907].
      Za.Y862.907e]
- "Z"
  - ZUKOFSKY, LOUIS, 1904-1978 (Box 31, Folder 1227)
    - The First Seasons, by Dunn Wyth [pseud.]. Typescript (carbon)
      71 leaf
      "...written by me ca. 1920-1924... not to be published...Louis Zukovsky, January. 23, 1941"